howdens.com 2019-05-14

# Privacy Policy | Howdens

We respect the privacy of every person who visits or registers with or submits personal information through our website at howdens.com (including myaccount.howdens.com and my-kitchen.howdens.com) (the “ **Site** ”) and who uses the products and services that we offer, including from the Site, and we are committed to ensuring a safe online experience.

* **PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE**

This Privacy Notice (“ **Privacy Notice** ”) explains our approach to any personal information that we might collect from you or which we have obtained about you from a third party and the purposes for which we process your personal information. This Privacy Notice also sets out your rights in respect of our processing of your personal information.

This Privacy Notice: 

  * informs you of the nature of the personal information about you that is processed by us and how you can request that we delete it, update it, transfer it and/or provide you with access to it; and 

  * is intended to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Site and our products and services. Please take a moment to read and understand it. It should be read in conjunction with our Website Terms of Use. 

This Privacy Notice only applies to the use of your personal information obtained by us; it does not apply to personal information collected during your communications with third parties.

* **ABOUT US**

The Site and our services are made available by Howden Joinery Limited (“ **Howdens** ”). Howdens is the data controller responsible for your personal information.

Howdens is a private limited company registered in England under company registration number 00526923 with its registered office address located at 40 Portman Square, London W1H 6LT. Howdens is registered as a data controller with the UK’s Information Commissioner’s Office under registration number Z6174295.

* **HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or want to exercise your rights set out in this Privacy Notice, please contact: legal@howdens.com

* **PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

Our primary reasons for collecting personal information from you is to: (i) provide our products and services to you; (ii) verify your identity (where applicable); (iii) help us improve our Site and our products and services and develop and market new products and services; (iv) carry out requests made by you on the Site; (v) investigate or settle enquiries or disputes; (vi) comply with applicable law, court order, other judicial process and the requirements of regulators; (vii) enforce our agreements with you; (viii) protect the rights, property and safety of us or third parties, including our other customers and users of the Site; (ix) provide support for the provision of our products and services; (x) carry out recruitment activities; and (xi) use as otherwise required or permitted by law.

In particular, we use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * **Fulfilment of our products and services**

We collect and maintain personal information that you voluntarily submit to us during your use of the Site and when you purchase products from us or use our services. 

**Account registration and log in:** If you register for a customer account with Howdens, we will use your trade account name and number, name, email address and postcode to process your registration. Once you are registered, we will process your email address and password to identify you when you log into secure areas of our Site. We will use your account information so that we can administer your account with us and we will use any payment details you enter so that we can make payments at your request.

**Kitchen design services:** If you request our home survey and kitchen design services, we will use your name and contact details (email address, postal address, telephone number) and any other information you volunteer in order to arrange and carry out a visit to your home to provide the service you have requested.

**Brochure requests:** We use your name and contact details (postal address or email address) to send you our brochures and other publications when you request them.

**Contact Your Local Depot:** We use your name and contact details (email address and phone number) to contact you about our products when you request a call back.

**Lamona after-sales service:** If you register for our Lamona appliance after-sales service, we will process your name, email address, postal address, telephone number and information about your purchase of the relevant product. If you make a warranty claim, we may process these details as well as any other relevant personal information you provide in order to process the warranty claim. If your builder or professional installer is making a warranty claim in relation to any Howdens products and services which they have supplied to you, we may need to collect personal information about you, such as your name, contact details and any other relevant information, in order to process their warranty claim.

**Who do we share your personal information with for this purpose?**

We will share your personal information with the following categories of third parties as necessary when supplying our products and services: 
    * **Credit card companies and other payment providers** who assist us with the verification of card payments and the processing of refunds;
    * **Delivery and courier companies** who assist us with delivering products to our customers;
    * **Printing companies** who provide label printing services, for example, when you request a brochure;
    * **Your builder or professional installer** whom we may need to cooperate with in relation to the products and services you have requested from them and us;
    * **Wifi providers** who assist us by providing free wifi to customers in our depots;
    * **Engineers** who assist us by providing aftersales support for our Lamona appliances; and
    * **Web hosting, optimisation and management companies** who assist us with the hosting, operation, optimisation and maintenance of our Site, the administration of your account with us and the provision of access to secure areas and functionality on our Site.

Please note this list is non-exhaustive and there may be circumstances where we need to share personal information with other third parties in order to provide the products and services as effectively as we can.

**What is our legal basis?**

It is necessary for us to use your personal information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you or it is in our legitimate interest or a third party’s legitimate interest to use personal information in such a way to ensure that we provide the products and services you have requested in an effective and efficient way.

  * **Customer services and enquiries**

Our Site and our depots use various user interfaces to allow you to request information about our products and services. Our enquiry services are accessible by mobile device, email, and telephone. When making an enquiry, the enquirer’s name and contact information (including email address, postal address, telephone number) may be requested, together with details of other personal information that is relevant to the enquiry. This information is used to enable us to manage and respond to your enquiries and requests. 

**Who do we share your personal information with for this purpose?**

We do not share your personal information for this purpose.

**What is our legal basis?**

It is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information in such a way to ensure that we provide good customer service to you.

  * **Your feedback about our products and services**

From time to time, we may invite you to provide feedback about our products and services in the form of online, postal or in-depot surveys. We will collect your name and contact details (email address, postal address, telephone number) and any other personal information you choose to volunteer in your feedback.

We use this information to help us improve the quality of customer service provided by our staff and in our depots. We also use your feedback to monitor the quality of our products and services and to assist with the selection of future product and service lines.

We also provide an online Website Feedback form which you can use to report technical issues with our Site. When you complete this form, we may capture your browser type and device type for diagnostic purposes and, where requested, your name, email address and details of the issue you wish to report. This feedback is used for the purposes of improving our website services.

**Who do we share your personal information with for this purpose?**

We may share your personal information with third party survey providers who prepare the surveys on our behalf and evaluate the results of the feedback you have provided. These third party providers are Good Growth and Hotjar.

We do not share the personal information you have provided in our Website Feedback form.

**What is our legal basis?**

It is in our legitimate interest to use the personal information provided by you in your feedback for the purposes described above.

  * **Customer insight and analysis**

We analyse your contact details with other personal information that we observe about you from your interactions with our Site and/or with our products and services, such as the products and services you have purchased or viewed, or from your use of our in-depot wifi.

Where you have given your consent (where lawfully required), we use cookies, log files and other technologies to collect personal information from the computer hardware and software you use to access the Site, or from your mobile device. This includes the following:

    * an IP address to monitor Site traffic and volume;
    * a session ID to track usage statistics on our Site; and
    * information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, buying habits, experiences with our products and contact preferences.

Our web pages may contain cookies, web beacons and pixel tags (“Tags”). Tags allow us to track receipt of an email to you, count users who have visited a web page and collect other types of aggregated information. Once you click on an email that contains a Tag, your contact information may subsequently be cross-referenced to the source email and/or the relevant Tag.

In some of our email messages, we use a “click-through URL” linked to certain websites administered by us or on our behalf. We may track click-through data to assist in determining interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of these communications. 

Please see our Cookie Policy  for further information. 

This information is used to create insights about our visitors’ browsing habits on our Site. Where we have your consent to do so, we will also use your location data for customer insight and analysis purposes.

By using this information, we are able to measure the effectiveness of our content and how visitors use our Site and our products and services. This allows us to learn what pages of our Site are most attractive to our visitors, which parts of our Site are the most interesting and what kind of features and functionalities our visitors and clients like to see. 

We also use this information to help us with the selection of future product and service lines and website design and to remember your preferences. 

We may also use this information for marketing purposes (see the “Marketing Activities” section below for further details).

**Who do we share your personal information with for these purposes?**

We share your personal information with third party service providers to assist us with insight analytics. These providers are described in our Cookie Policy.

**What is our legal basis?**

Where your personal information is completely anonymised, we do not require a legal basis to use it as the information will no longer constitute personal information that is regulated under data protection laws. However, our collection and use of such anonymised personal information may be subject to other laws where your consent is required. Please see our Cookie Policy for further details. 

Where your personal information is not in an anonymous form, it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information in such a way to ensure that we provide good quality products and services to you and our other visitors and clients.

We will only use your location data for insight and analysis purposes where we have your consent to do so.

  * **Marketing activities**

We may carry out the following marketing activities using your personal information:

**Prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions**

From time to time, we may run prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions on our Site, on our social media accounts and/or in our depots. For the purposes of administering such promotions, we may process your name, contact details (including email address, postal address and/or telephone number), social media handle (if relevant) and any other personal information volunteered by you in your promotion entry.

**Who do we share your personal information with for these purposes?**

We may share your personal information collected in connection with any prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions that we run with any third party providers that assist us with the administration of such promotions.

**What is our legal basis?**

It is necessary for us to use your personal information to perform our obligations in accordance with any contract that we may have with you (e.g. the terms and conditions applicable to the promotion) or it is in our legitimate interest to use your personal information to enable you to participate in any prize draws, prize competitions and other promotions.

  * **Recruitment**

If you are applying for a position through Howdens’ careers portal at careers.howdens.com (“ **Careers Site** ”), the privacy notice displayed on the Careers Site will apply to the processing of your personal information in relation to your status as an applicant and your use of the Careers Site.

  * **Business administration and legal compliance**

We use your personal information for the following business administration and legal compliance purposes:

    * to comply with our legal obligations; 
    * to enforce our legal rights; 
    * to protect the rights of third parties; and 
    * in connection with a business transition such as a merger, reorganisation, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets. 

**Who do we share your personal information with for these purposes?**

We will share your personal information with professional advisers such as lawyers and accountants and/or governmental or regulatory authorities.

We may also share personal information with other entities within the Howdens group of companies for these purposes. 

**What is our legal basis?**

Where we use your personal information in connection with a business transition, to enforce our legal rights or to protect the rights of third parties, it is in our legitimate interest to do so. For all other purposes described in this section, it is our legal obligation to use your personal information to comply with any legal obligations imposed upon us such as a court order.

We will not process any special (or sensitive) categories of personal information or personal information relating to criminal convictions or offences except where we are able to do so under applicable legislation or with your explicit consent.

  * **Investor relations**

This Privacy Notice applies to you if you are a customer or client of Howdens and/or a user of the Site.

If you are a shareholder in Howden Joinery Group Plc and/or a user of the website at howdenjoinerygroupplc.com (“ **Corporate Site** ”), the privacy notice displayed on the Corporate Site will apply to the processing of your personal information in relation to your status as an investor and your use of the Corporate Site. The data controller responsible for your personal information in relation to this processing is Howden Joinery Group Plc.

Howden Joinery Group Plc is a public limited company registered in England under company registration number 02128710 with its registered office address located at 40 Portman Square, London W1H 6LT. Howden Joinery Group Plc is registered as a data controller with the UK’s Information Commissioner’s Office under registration number Z6396228.

  * **Any other purposes for which we wish to use your personal information that are not listed above, or any other changes we propose to make to the existing purposes, will be notified to you using your contact details**

* **HOW WE OBTAIN YOUR CONSENT**

Where our use of your personal information requires your consent, you can provide such consent: 

  * at the time we collect your personal information following the instructions provided; or
  * by informing us by email, post or telephone using the contact details set out in the “How to Contact Us” section above

* **OUR USE OF COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGIES**

Our Site may use certain cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files and other technologies. Please see our Cookie Policy to find out more about the cookies and other technologies we use, the purposes for which we use them and how to manage, block or delete them.

* **THIRD PARTY LINKS AND SERVICES**

Our Site contains links to third party websites and services. When you use a link to go from our Site to another website or you request a service from a third party, this Privacy Notice no longer applies.

Your browsing and interaction on any other websites, or your dealings with any other third party service provider, is subject to that website’s or third party service provider’s own rules and policies.

We do not monitor, control or endorse the privacy practices of any third parties.

We encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of every website you visit or third party service provider that you deal with and to contact them if you have any questions about their respective privacy notices and practices.

This Privacy Notice applies solely to personal information collected by us through our Site and/or the supply of our products and services and does not apply to these third party websites and third party service providers.

* **TRANSFERS OUTSIDE THE EEA**

We do not transfer the personal data you submit on our Site outside the European Economic Area.

* **HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Regarding personal information we have processed in connection with the Contact Your Local Depot and request a Brochure Sections of the Site, we will retain personal information relevant to that request for 18 months from the date of the request. We may then destroy such files without further notice or liability.

Regarding any other personal information we have processed, we will keep your personal data for as long as we need it for the purpose it is being processed for and in compliance with our obligations under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (or similar legislation around the world). For example, any personal data collected as part of the Register Your Appliance from on the Site will be retained indefinitely unless you ask us to delete your information, for the purposes of product safety and product recall.

We may then destroy such files without further notice or liability.

If any personal information is only useful for a short period (e.g. for a specific marketing campaign), we may delete it at the end of that period.

If you have opted out of receiving marketing communications from us, we will need to retain certain personal information indefinitely so we do not send you marketing communications again.

* **CONFIDENTIALITY AND SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We are committed to keeping the personal information you provide to us secure and we will take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We have implemented information security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal information that we have under our control from: 

  * unauthorised access;
  * improper use or disclosure;
  * unauthorised modification; and
  * unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors (i.e. those who process your personal information on our behalf, for the purposes listed above) who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal information are obliged to respect the confidentiality of the personal information of all users of our Site and our Services.

* **HOW TO ACCESS YOUR INFORMATION AND YOUR OTHER RIGHTS**

You have the following rights in relation to the personal information we hold about you:

  * **Your right of access**

If you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your personal information and, if so, provide you with a copy of that personal information (along with certain other details). If you require additional copies, we may charge a reasonable fee for producing those additional copies.

  * **Your right to rectification**

If the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to have it rectified. If we have shared your personal information with others, we’ll let them know about the rectification where possible. If you ask us, where possible and lawful to do so, we will also tell you who we’ve shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

  * **Your right to erasure**

You can ask us to delete or remove your personal information in some circumstances, such as where we no longer need it or where you withdraw your consent (where applicable). If we have shared your personal information with others, we will let them know about the erasure where possible. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

  * **Your right to restrict processing**

You can ask us to block or suppress the processing of your personal information in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of that personal information or you object to us processing it. It won’t stop us from storing your personal information, though. We will tell you before we lift any restriction. If we have shared your personal information with others, we will let them know about the restriction where it is possible for us to do so. If you ask us, where it is possible and lawful for us to do so, we will also tell you who we have shared your personal information with so that you can contact them directly.

  * **Your right to data portability**

With effect from 25 May 2018, you have the right, in certain circumstances, to obtain personal information you have provided to us (in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format) and to reuse it elsewhere or to ask us to transfer it to a third party of your choice.

  * **Your right to object**

You can ask us to stop processing your personal information, and we will do so, if we are:

    * relying on our own or someone else’s legitimate interest to process your personal information, except if we can demonstrate compelling legal grounds for the processing;
    * processing your personal information for the purposes of personalised direct marketing; or
    * processing your personal information for the purposes of non-personalised direct marketing.
  * **

Your rights in relation to automated decision-making and profiling

**

You have the right not to be subject to a decision when it is based on automatic processing, including profiling, if it produces a legal effect or similarly significantly affects you, unless such profiling is necessary for the entering into, or the performance of, a contract between you and us.

  * **Your right to withdraw consent**

If we rely on your consent (or explicit consent) as our legal basis for processing your personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. You can exercise your right of withdrawal by contacting us using our contact details in the “How to Contact Us” section above or by using any other opt-out mechanism we may provide, such as an unsubscribe link in an email.

  * **Your right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority**

If you have a concern about any aspect of our privacy practices, including the way we have handled your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided in the “How to Contact Us” section above. You can also report any issues or concerns to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). You can find details about how to report a concern on the ICO website at <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/> or by calling their helpline on 0303 123 1113.

* **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY NOTICE**

We may make changes to this Privacy Notice from time to time.

To ensure that you are always aware of how we use your personal information we will update this Privacy Notice from time to time to reflect any changes to our use of your personal information. We may also make changes as required to comply with changes in applicable law or regulatory requirements. We will notify you by email of any significant changes. However, we encourage you to review this Privacy Notice periodically to be informed of how we use your personal information.

Version: 2.1

Last Updated: 30 October 2018
